PRIYANKA SHAH

Resides: Ahmedabad, India Phone: +91- 966 2733 466

Email: priyankanioh82@gmail.com / shahpriyanka@iiphg.org

Nationality: Indian

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-shah-a8b91518/

Skype: Priyankanioh82@gmail.com

KEY SKILLS PRO

PROFILE SNAPSHOT

Research & Development
Proof Reading
Report Writing
Statistical Analysis
Qualitative Studies
Scientific Reports writing
Analytical Development
Data Management
Training and Development
Research & Analysis
Life Science Techniques
Publications
Regulatory & Safety Compliance
Environmental Hazards

Experience: Analytical & highly skilled Research professional offering more than **10+ years** of extensive experience in Research & Analysis, Statistical Analysis, Scientific Reports Writing, Qualitative Studies, Project management, Life Science and Occupational Medical Techniques. Profound experience in performing life science techniques including Malaria screening using microscopy, ELISA technique, HPLC and PCR, blotting methods, Cell culture techniques and Biochemical estimation of blood.

Expertise: Dexterous in carrying out 3D Motion Analysis, Gait laboratory, Piezoelectric force platform (Kistler), Surface Electromyography (SEMG), Isokinetic and Rehabilitation system, Whole Body 3D Scanner, SensoMotoric Instruments -Eye movement tracker, Microclimate analysis, Pulmonary Function Test (PFT), Audiogram, and other software related to all these instruments.

Deft in managing complex studies in various scientific areas and efficient in managing and tracking regulatory documentation, and confidentiality disclosure agreements. Impeccable in planning requirements to support all aspects of senior management's work, conducting meetings including statistical analysis of scientific data, interpretation/compiling of research work, technical writing of scientific publications, original articles, reviews, specific scientific literature searches, preparing of research protocols

EDUCATION

Master of Philosophy in Zoology from Gujarat University, India, 2007

Master of Science in Zoology-Molecular Endocrinology and Reproductive Physiology from Gujarat University, India, 2005 **Competency:** Key Strengths includes: attention to detail, critical thinking, deductive reasoning, management and strategy abilities and experience in utilizing environmental parameter measurements via Area Heat Stress Monitor, Infrared Thermographic camera, Data- logger, and software related to all these instruments. Record of working efficiently and handled multiple assignments with competing priorities, often under considerable pressure to meet deadlines

Bachelor of Science in Zoology from Gujarat University, India, 2003 Demonstrated excellent communication/problem solving/analytical skills while recruiting, mentoring and providing strong hands-on experience on various tasks to the team to ensure effective service delivery throughout the research lifecycle.

EXPERIENCE

August - 2021 - Ongoing

Project Assistant at Indian Institute of Public Health, India

• Surveillance for Enteric Fever in India (SEFI) Tertiary Care Surveillance (Tier III). Jun 2019-July 2021

Research Associate & Consultant at Indian Institute of Public Health, India

- Involved in Climate Change & Heat Action Plan project sponsored by Department of Science and Technology
- Conducted research using various resources like archives, collections & other sources of information to collect/ record/ analyze & evaluate facts.
- Monitored and climate change-related mortality & morbidity data and preparation and application of "Heat Action Plan" for Central and Western Indian cities

May 2018- Apr 2019

Medical Writer at Medip Academy, India

CERTIFICATION

R Programming & Data Analytics from Vnurture Technologies, India, 2020

- Analyzed and examined scientific articles, proof-read and cross-checked the documents for grammatical errors and edited accordingly
- Ensured the content, format and structure of the documents comply with regulatory, journal or other guidelines
- Liaised directly with clients and authors/speakers on various projects

Apr 2017- Feb 2018

Senior Research Fellow at Nirma University, India

- Performed a wide array of duties like managed microscopy, blood & stool samples and assisted in smear preparation & assessed malaria in blood sample
- Utilized molecular biology & analytical techniques and carried out statistical analysis as well
- Prepared reports & recorded publications on the findings

Feb 2008- Mar 2017

Senior Research Fellow at National Institute of Occupational Health, India

- Worked as Lab Technician, Technician and Research Assistant for ICAR/ ICMR/ WHO/ GGP sponsored projects
- Executed 3D motion analysis, gait laboratory, Piezoelectric force platform (Kistler), Surface EMG, EEG, Isokinetic and Rehabilitation system, Whole Body 3D Scanner, SMI-Eye movement tracker, Spirometry (PFT), Audiometry, Area Heat Stress Monitor, Infrared Thermographic camera, Data- logger using several software for these instruments
- Conducted field surveys on Human factors & Ergonomics, Biological and Anthropology and developed questionnaire/survey checklist keeping the protocols in mind
- Effectively handled physiological & biomechanical instruments like WBGT, Infrared Cameras & thermal scanners to record environmental parameter measurements

PRECEDING ASSIGNMENTS

Nov 2006- Jan 2008

Trainee Clinical Business Associate at Unichem Laboratories, India Field Officer at Cadila Pharmaceuticals, India

Oversaw and managed the marketing of pharmaceutical products

Jun 2006- Nov 2006

Visiting lecturer (Contractual) at K.K. Shah Jarodwala Maninagar Science College, India

- Provided assistance to UG students in executing laboratory work & other practical works in Biology
- Delivered lectures to UG students as well

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

- Study on the possible factors related to declining trends in fertility A Review. (M.Phil. dissertation- 2007)
- Work Practice and health hazards of women in fish processing works in coastal regions (Indian Council of Agriculture Research (ICAR) funded Project - 2008 - 2009)
- To study and analyze the health impact of climate changes and to provide new evidence that can be used in health impact assessment within member countries of the South East Asia Region (WHO sponsored project -2010)
- Industrial and dress footwear characteristics and its influence on postural stability.
 (Electromyographic and stabilometric analysis) (Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) sponsored Project 2010-2012)
- Health of workers in Ceramic industry and Iron foundries (Govt. of Gujarat sponsored project - 2013-2015)
- A study of knowledge, attitude and perception of young Indian men towards females about gender discrepancy at work (ICMR sponsored project - 2015 - 2017)
- Epidemiology of Anaemia in Pre-school Tribal children of Eastern Gujarat with Reference to Etiology, Pathophysiology and Nutritional Impact (ICMR sponsored project-2017-2018).

PUBLICATIONS/REPORTS/ CONFERENCES/ TRAINING



• Heat Action Plan (Department of Science and Technology- DST sponsored project 2019-2021)

Publication List:

- Influence of footwear on stabilometric dimensions and muscle activity. Nag P, Nag A, Vyas H, Shah
 Shukla P. Footwear Science. 2011. 3(3): 179-188.
- Perceived heat stress and strain of workers. Nag P, Nag A, Shekhar P, Shah P. Asian Pacific Newsletter of Occupational Health. 2011. 18(1): 18-20.
- Risk factors and Musculoskeletal disorders among women workers performing fish processing.
 Nag A, Vyas H, Shah P, Nag P. American Journal of Industrial Medicine. 2012. 55(2): 833-843.
- Postural control in unstable sitting. Nag P, Nag A, Vyas H, Shah P. International Journal of Human Factors and Ergonomics. 2012. 1(3): 254-267.
- Disparity of seat cushion and its influence on postural control. Nag P, Nag A, Vyas H, Shah P.
 International Journal of Occupational Safety and Ergonomics. 2013. 19(4): 573-581.
- Occupation, participation, inclusion, work role Postural control in different load handling tasks.
 Nag P, Nag A, Vyas H, Shah P. Work. 2014. 49(4): 577-584.
- Attitudes and perception of young working men on Gender discrepancy. Bagepally, BS, Majumder, J, Shah P, Patel RC, Kotadiya, S. International Journal of Preventive, Curative & Community Medicine. 2015. 1(3): 27-30. ISSN: 2454-325X.
- Heat Stress Vulnerability among Indian Workmen. 2016. J Majumder, Shah P, Kumar S. In S, Dind (Ed.), Handbook of Research on Climate Change Impact on Health and Environmental Sustainability, IGI Global Publishers, PA 17033-1240, USA, p 62-81, ISBN 978-1-4666-8814-8; DOI: 10.4018/978-1-4666-8814-8.ch004. (Book chapter).
- Comparison of workers' perception towards work climate and health symptoms between ceramic
 and iron foundry workers. J Majumder, Bagepally B, Shah P, Kotadiya S, Yadav S, Naha N. Indian
 Journal of Occupational and Environmental Medicine. 2016. 20(1): 48-53.
- Task distribution, work environment and perceived health discomforts among Indian ceramic workers. J Majumder, Shah P, Bagepally B - American Journal of Industrial Medicine. 2016. 59:1145–1155.
- Longitudinal risk estimate of hearing impairment among workforce in quite office environment. J Majumder, Patel RC, Kotadiya S, Shah P. 2016. Age (years), 42(12.4), 38-8.
- Mapping the role of Women in Indian Agriculture. J Majumder, Shah P. Annals of Anthropological Practice. 2017. 41(2):46-54.
- Hearing threshold status and risk estimate of hearing impairment among administrative workforce.
 J Majumder, Patel RC, Kotadiya S, Shah P. Indian Journal of Occupational and Environmental Medicine. 2018. 22(1): 11-16.
- India's Heat Health Action Plan: A successful public health policy response to extreme heat events.
 Golechha M, Shah P, Saunik S, Mavalankar D. 2021. Health adaptation and resilience with reference to climate change and related disasters (Compendium of Case Studies). ISBN No. 978-93-82571-52-0. (Book chapter).
- Threshold determination and temperature trends analysis of Indian cities for effective implementation of an early warning system. Golechha M, Shah P, Mavalankar D. Urban Climate. Sep-2021. 39: 100934).

Conference & Training:

- "Biomedical Technology- An Update" at Gujarat University on 3rd- 4th Feb- 2005.
- "Clinical Trial and Statistical Analysis" at National Institute of Occupational Health on 24th -27th Feb- 2011.
- Orientation Training Programme on Ergonomic Instrumentation at National Institute of Occupational Health on 9th -20th June 2014.
- Poster presentation at International Conference on Reproductive Health with Emphasis on Occupational, Environmental and Life style factors & Annual meeting of Indian Society for the study of Reproduction & Fertility on 18th- 20th Feb-2016.
- Paper presentation at the National Seminar on Environment and Occupational Health on 5th-6th June-2016.